ivypanda.com 2019-10-15

# IvyPanda | Privacy Policy | Cookies Policy

IvyPanda.com has compiled this privacy policy for you to better understand how your Personal Information is being used online. 

By reading this section, you will understand what information we collect about you when you’re using IvyPanda’s website, products, and services, how we keep it, how we use it, and when and how we may share it. 

## What is Personally Identifiable Information (PII)?

[Personally Identifiable Information (PII)](https://nvlpubs.nist.gov/nistpubs/Legacy/SP/nistspecialpublication800-122.pdf "Personally Identifiable Information \(PII\)"), as described in US privacy law and information security, can be used for identifying, locating or contacting a specific person, or for identifying an individual in context.

## What personal information do we collect?

When you use IvyPanda.com’s website, blog, and services, we may ask you to provide your phone number, email address, or other details to help you with your experience.

All User submitted information to IvyPanda will be stored in our database, excluding your payment information.

You may access and change any provided information via your personal account. We ask you to keep your data updated and submit only valid means of contact.

If you wish us to delete all your data and database records, please contact us via email [support@ivypanda.com](mailto:support@ivypanda.com "Support email"). Your records will be removed in two business days.

We collect personal information, any necessary information to perform your requests, including but not limited to data you share when interacting with service providers, name, date of birth, gender, etc.

If you upload videos or photos on IvyPanda.com, we may collect additional data or metadata, including but not limited to the date, time, and place the photo or video was taken.

We do not collect or keep, nor have access to your bank accounts or credit card. All transactions are handled by third-party services (i.e., Stripe) through a gateway provider and are not stored or processed on IvyPanda’s servers.

## When do we collect information?

IvyPanda.com gathers personal information that you enter when you register, sign up for a newsletter, complete a survey or other marketing communication, make a purchase, etc.

## How do we use your information?

We may use your email address for the following, but not limited, purposes:

  * sending newsletters, materials, and responding to requests or inquiries
  * processing orders and sending any information and updates related to orders
  * sending additional information related to IvyPanda’s products and/or services 
  * follow up with you after communication (live chat, email or phone inquiries, etc).

The [CAN-SPAM Act](https://www.ftc.gov/tips-advice/business-center/guidance/can-spam-act-compliance-guide-business "CAN-SPAM Act") sets the rules for commercial email, establishes requirements for commercial messages, gives recipients the right to have emails stopped from being sent to them, and spells out tough penalties for violations.

In accordance with the CAN-SPAM Act, we attempt to:

  * avoid using misleading or false email addresses or subjects
  * designate the message as an advertisement in a reasonable way
  * put the physical address of our site headquarters or our business in messages
  * check third-party email marketing services for compliance, when one is used
  * process unsubscribe/opt-out requests quickly
  * include an unsubscribe link at the bottom of each email

If you do not want us to send you emails anymore, follow the instructions in the unsubscribe link at the bottom of our emails. Your email address will be removed from all correspondence and subscriptions. 

## How do we protect your information?

We scan IvyPanda.com on a regular basis for malware, viruses, security holes, and other known vulnerabilities to make your online surfing as safe as possible.

We store your personal information and data records behind secured networks. Only a limited number of IvyPanda’s employees have special access to these systems and are required to keep the information confidential.

All credit or other sensitive information is encrypted via SSL (Secure Sockets Layer) technology.

In case a data breach occurred, we will take the following responsive actions:

  * Notify users, subscribers, vendors, and other IvyPanda.com users via email within seven business days. 
  * We will notify IvyPanda.com visitors, users, vendors, or other users of the website and its services via in-site notification within one business day. 

## Do we use Cookies, Pixels, or other technologies?

Cookies are small pieces of data stored on your computer, mobile phone, or other device which enable service providers or website systems to identify your browser and capture and collect certain information.

Pixels are small blocks of code on web pages that allow servers to measure a web page’s viewing and often are used in connection with cookies.

We use pixels, cookies, and local storage (which is similar to a cookie but collects and holds more information) to gather information about your behavior on the IvyPanda.com website, including but not limited to pages you viewed, links you clicked, your IP address, location, date and time you visited our website, track ad campaign performance and efficiency, and deliver relevant ads.

Cookies and pixels that we use include, but are not limited to:

  * AdRoll
  * Facebook
  * Google
  * Yandex
  * Twitter

In your browser’s Settings menu, you can turn off all cookies or choose to have your computer warn you each time a cookie is being sent.

By turning off cookies, you understand and agree that some features which make your IvyPanda.com experience more efficient may not perform properly.

## Third-party disclosure

We do not trade, sell, or otherwise transfer to third-parties IvyPanda users’ personally identifiable information except IvyPanda.com hosting partners and other parties assisting us in running our website, our services, or conducting our business, as long as those parties agree to keep this information confidential.

We reserve the right to release user’s information when is appropriate to comply with the law, accomplish IvyPanda’s policies, or secure ours or others' rights, safety, or property.

Nevertheless, we may provide to other parties visitors’ information apart from PII for advertising, marketing, or other purposes.

## How does IvyPanda.com handle Do Not Track signals?

When a DNT (Do Not Track) browser mechanism is turned on, we do not track that user’s activities, use advertising, or plant cookies.

## Does our site allow third-party behavioral tracking?

IvyPanda.com does not enable third-party behavioral tracking, including but not limited to demographics, pages you viewed, links you clicked, your IP address, location, and date and time you have visited our website.

## How does IvyPanda.com protect children's privacy and safety online?

We do not specifically market, nor collect personal information from children under the age of 13 years old.

For questions related to this privacy policy, contact us via email at [support@ivypanda.com](mailto:support@ivypanda.com "Support email").
